一架吊车在特伦顿市区倒坍了
A crane collapsed in downtown Trenton.
不关我的事
Don't care.
是我曾祖父
That's my great-grandfather.
不  就是本他写的书
No, it's just a book he wrote.
打开看看
Open it up.
致丽莎和卢卡斯,
翻开人生的新篇章 -- 格雷戈
当真吗  你要把这个给我们吗
Seriously, you're giving this to us?
对你们而言可是迈出了很大一步
It's a big step you're taking.
我想要恭喜你们
I wanted to congratulate you.
我明白这是成年人该做的
I understand that's the adult thing to do.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我知道有段时间了
I've known for a while.
你们决定同居的事儿
The fact that you decided to cohabitate
算不上是新闻了
is not exactly a spoiler.
除非我的小道消息有误
Unless my intel is wrong.
天堂里的烦恼[喜剧  甜蜜期后出现问题]
Trouble in paradise?
我们得去特伦顿了
We have to get to Trenton.
你能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
嗯
Hmm?
她这是听见了吗
That sound like a yes?
先生  我们得送你去手术室
Sir, we have to get you to the O.R.
你的伤势很严重  不过我们会简单包扎
You have a bad wound, but we're gonna pack it
然后尽快送你过去
and transport you as fast as we can.
颅骨骨折  格拉斯哥昏迷指数十一
Skull fracture. Glasgow coma score of 11.
她是紧急伤员
She's immediate.
放弃他吧
Move on.
-救不活了  -他的伤势不是那么
- This guy's dead. - His wounds aren't so
别管伤了  看看他的脚趾
Forget the wound. Look at his toes.
动脉粥样硬化栓塞  他撑不过手术的
Atherosclerotic emboli. He'll never survive the surgery.
或许是因为他的鞋子太紧
Maybe his shoes were too tight.
和鞋子无关  皮肤上有烟斑
It's not the shoes. Skin shows smoker's facies.
他熬不到早上
He's not gonna make it till morning.
只会让救护车白跑一趟
He'll just take up an ambulance ride,
浪费手术时间和重症监护室的床位
surgeon's time, and an ICU bed.
他没救了  别管他了
He's expectant. Leave him.
我就打了一下盹
I only nodded off for a second.
装载负荷失了控  我很抱歉
I lost control of the load. I'm so sorry.
别担心  我们会把你救出来的
Don't worry. We're gonna get you outta here.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
绑好了
He's secure.
准备好了吗  三  二  一
Ready? Three, two, one.
好了
That's it.
吊车操作员  成功脱险伤势不重
Crane operator. Made it through amazingly well.
神志清醒  有反映
Lucid and responsive.
右侧肱骨稳定性骨折
Stable fracture, right humerus.
下半身还没检查
Haven't gotten to his lower half yet.
哪里疼的话告诉我
Tell me when something hurts.
我睡着了  害死了所有那些人
I fell asleep. Killed all those people.
除了你良心受责备的痛
Something other than your conscience.
你口袋里是药片吗
Is that a pill in your pocket,
还是你碰巧长了个
Or are you just happy to have
袖珍药片状的鸡鸡
a tiny pill-shaped penis?
咖啡因片
Caffeine pills.
吃这些你还睡着了吗
You fell asleep taking these?
我还喝了两杯咖啡
I drank two cups of coffee too.
你平常就这样吗
Is that normal for you?
不  我讨厌咖啡
No, I hate coffee.
我晚上没睡就出车了
I'm working on no sleep.
我女儿感冒了
My daughter has the flu.
那么多咖啡因对于一个不喝咖啡的人来说
This much caffeine for a coffee virgin.
他不可能睡着  他晕过去了
There's no way he fell asleep. He passed out.
因此是神经性失调
Which means a neurological disorder
导致了事故  而非疲劳
Caused the crash, not fatigue.
嘿
Hey.
我们要带吊车操作员回普林斯顿
We're taking the crane operator back to Princeton.
他们说他几乎没受伤  他可以等的
They said he was barely hurt--he can wait.
偷辆救护车  通知小组成员
Steal an ambulance. And call the team.
告诉他们我们有病例了
Tell 'em we got a case.
豪斯  不行  我需要你在这里
House. No! I need you here.
而他需要我在那里  他叫唤得比你厉害
And he needs me there. And he moans louder than you do.
那栋房子下压着一百多个人呢
There were over 100 people in that building.
目前才找到七十六个
Only 76 have been accounted for.
福曼和你的组员可以暂时处理吊车操作员
Foreman and your team can handle the crane operator for now.
那里有意思吗
Having fun down there?
非常
lots!
每次卡迪俯身检查病人
Every time cuddy leans over a patient,
就是个看她春光乍泄的好机会
it's another opportunity for a down blouse nip slip.
她和卢卡斯怎么了
What's going on between her and lucas?
除了他们要同居吗
Besides them moving in together?
对你而言还不够吗
That's not enough for you?
我早些时候把祝贺乔迁的礼物给她了
I gave her the housewarming gift earlier.
她愣了一下
And she paused for a split second,
像是在隐瞒什么
Like she was hiding something.
可能是她不喜欢
It's probably her moral revulsion
乔迁贺礼这套吧
at housewarming gifts.
又或许她不想收下为了祝贺
Or maybe she didn't want to accept a gift
她不想做的事的贺礼
for something she wasn't gonna do.
你真觉着他们不会同居吗
You actually think they're not moving in together?
什么声音  你没事吧
What was that? You okay?
没事  自动售货机塌了
Yep. Vending machine collapsed.
你的前妻还是她的房产经纪人吗
She still using your ex-wife as a realtor?
据我所知还是
As far as I know.
那么  就再深入点  行吗
Well, know a little farther, will you?
多挖点内幕
Look into it.
嘿
Hey!
那里下面有人
There's somebody down here!
你能听到我的话
If you can hear me,
就敲三下  或者喊出来
tap three times, or call out.
下面有人吗
Is anyone there?
我什么也听不到
I'm not getting anything.
我听到了  下面肯定有空隙
I heard something--there's gotta be a void down there.
这下面有无数个空隙呢
There's a million voids down there.
那是个停车场
It was the parking garage.
但是仪器没有探测到任何动静
But equipment hasn't picked up any movement.
搜救犬也没有闻出什么
Dogs haven't picked up any scent.
下面有被压扁的车
There's smashed cars down there.
汽油会掩盖气味吗
The gasoline throw off their scent?
听着  我们得回去工作了  行吗
Look, we gotta get back to work, okay?
我们会尽快到达这个区域的  借过
We'll get to this area soon. Excuse me.
有人能听到我吗
Anybody hear me?
嘿
Hey!
有人能听到我吗
Anybody hear me?
救救我
help me.
你叫什么
What's your name?
求你  我丈夫的礼物
Please...my husband's gift.
我原该去装裱的地方取的
I was supposed to pick it up at the framers.
在伊尔姆大街
It's on Elm.
你该早点告诉我的
Well, you should have told me earlier.
我就能顺道帮你取了
I could have picked it up on the way.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我们去托托拉岛旅游的照片
It's a picture from our tortola trip.
他的生日礼物
For his birthday.
我问你名字不是为了交朋友
I'm not asking your name because I wanna become friends.
是为了判断你的精神状态
I'm trying to gauge your mental state.
汉娜
Hanna.
很好  不错的开端  今天周几
Okay, that's a start. What day of the week is it?
周二
Tuesday.
更好了
Better still.
发生了什么事
What happened?
知道旁边工地上那架巨型吊车吗
You know that giant construction crane next door?
正塌在你头顶上
It's kind of on top of you right now.
好了  我要试着把你拖出来
Okay, I'm gonna try to pull you out.
我的腿
Ow! My leg!
好了好了
Okay, okay.
我得去找人帮忙
I'm gonna need to get help.
不  别走  会有人来的
No, stay! Someone else will come.
没人知道我在下面
No one knows I'm down here.
求你  别离开
Please! Stay with me.
别把我丢在黑暗里
Don't leave me in the dark.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
不  别把我丢在黑暗里
No! Don't leave me in the dark!
求你别走
Please stay!
豪斯  他还在急诊室
He's still in the E.R., House.
我们太忙还没开始鉴别诊断
We haven't had time to start a differential.
好极了  现在开始
Perfect! Let's start right now.
打开扬声器
Put me on speaker.
什么能引发昏厥
What causes syncope?
他现在情况稳定  那边还有二十多位病人
Your guy's stable. The two dozen other patients...
不需要你们诊断
Don't need to be diagnosed.
包扎一下就好
They just need to be bandaged.
什么能引发昏厥
What causes syncope?
血管迷走反应
Vasovagal reaction...
脑膜瘤  病窦结综合征
Meningioma. Sick sinus syndrome.
或者你错了  他只是睡过去了而已
Or you're wrong, and he just fell asleep.
血管里流着五十杯咖啡
How's he gonna sleep with
你说他怎么睡过去的
50 cups of coffee going through his veins?
你就没在医院值过夜班吗
Were you never a medical resident?
10  11  和12发表意见了
I hear ten, eleven, and twelve.
-13在哪儿  -她不在
- Where's thirteen? - She's not here.
你下一个问题的答案也是不
And the answer to your next question is no.
我不知道她在哪儿
I don't know where she is.
我再下个问题的答案你也知道了吗
Do you have the answer to my question after that?
多半是脑部占位性病变
Space-occupying lesion in his brain is most likely.
磁共振会证明我的推断
MRI will prove I'm right.
或者证明他的头部在事故中受到了损伤
Or it'll just prove he suffered head trauma from the crash.
这个反正也是要查的
Which we'd wanna find anyway.
一振二鸟  去吧
Two birds with one scan. Do it.
试图给汉娜输液  找不到静脉
Having trouble finding a vein for Hanna's IV.
她变虚弱了
She getting weaker?
-脸色变差了  -没有  她很稳定
- Paler? - No, no. She's stable.
就是说她没有大出血
That means her blood loss in minimal.
为我们争取了时间抢救
Buys us some time.
直接从胫骨注射
Get the IV into her tibia.
胫骨内部几乎是空的  与静脉系统直接相连
It's almost hollow, feeds into the venous system.
显然急救医疗学校不教这个
Which they obviously don't teach you in EMT school.
这边还是倾斜得厉害
This side's still leaning pretty bad.
这根梁需要支撑
Gotta shore up this beam.
我说过会回来的吧
Told ya I'd be back.
听说你可能会渴
Heard you might be thirsty.
我猜你这叹的是救援成功的好兆头
I assume that bodes well for the rescue?
承重梁  高密度混凝土
Structural beam. High compression concrete.
我弄不断它
I can't break it up.
你没法救我出去
You can't get me outta here?
不  我只是需要
Naw. Just means we gotta move on
过去换件设备
to a different piece of equipment.
我有能起重七十吨的气囊
I got airbags comin' in that'll lift 70 tons.
你叫什么
What's your name?
你也在测试我的精神状态
You testing my mental state?
我还得在这困一阵子
I'm gonna be stuck down here for a while.
我想有个人说说话
I'd like somebody to talk to.
听着  刚刚出去那位才是
Look, the guy who just left is the one
握着你手陪你度过难关的人选
who's gonna be holding your hand through all this.
跟他说去吧
You talk to him.
会有点疼
Little pinch.
好吧  非常疼
Oh... okay. Big pinch.
我得给我丈夫打电话
I gotta call my husband.
能用你的手机吗
Can I use your phone?
下边儿没信号
Uh, no bars down here.
为生命喝彩
L'Chaim.
-你去哪儿  -别害怕
- Where are you going? - Don't worry.
烈火元帅比尔马上回来[金凯利饰演的喜剧角色]
Fire Marshal Bill will be back soon.
希望我送的那份礼物
So I hope I didn't weird you out
没让你觉得莫名其妙
giving you that gift.
我们过一会儿再说不行吗
Can we talk about this later?
当然
Of course.
一会儿过了吗
Is now later?
或许你跟卢卡斯进展不顺利
Maybe things aren't going so well with Lucas.
如果是这样  我很遗憾
If so, I'm sorry.
我无意干涉
I didn't mean to step into anything.
没有任何问题  我们融洽得很
There's no problems. We're doing just great.
谢谢
Thank you.
那你为什么怪怪的
So why the weirdness?
帮个忙好吗
Can you help?
我翻开书时
When I opened it,
我想的不是乔迁贺礼
I didn't think it was a housewarming gift.
而是订婚礼物
I thought it was an engagement present.
我们昨晚订婚的
It just happened last night.
怪不得你在我面前遮遮掩掩
No wonder you wanna hide this from me...
怕伤害我这棵娇弱的花朵
Since I'm such a delicate flower.
我不知该怎么说
I didn't know what to say.
而且正好这里的事要我操心
And I've been slightly distracted.
还算说得通
That might make sense,
只是你没戴戒指
'cept you're not wearing the ring.
所以呢  你还是在遮掩
So...you are hiding it,
因此我必须要问...
which begs the question...
豪斯  戒指在我办公室抽屉里
House...it's in my office drawer
我知道要到这来所以摘了
because I knew I was coming here.
没什么怪的
It's not weird.
没什么隐情
There's no mystery.
只是我要结婚了
I'm just getting married.
抱歉打扰一下
Excuse me.
还有多长时间
How much longer?
不到一分钟
Uh, less than a minute.
你疼吗
Are you in any pain?
现在不疼  只是有点幽闭空间恐惧
Nothing now. Just a little claustrophobic.
难道你们不去救治那些
Shouldn't you be taking care of those other people,
因我受伤的人吗
the ones that I hurt?
检查完毕  各项正常
Everything checks out okay.
我流鼻血了
My nose is bleeding.
应该的  因为你受了外伤
It's expected, given the trauma you've sustained.
这就不应该了
That's not expected.
发生倒塌后  是这条主梁
The way things fell, this support beam
撑起这一大堆碎石
is now holding up a giant pile of rubble.
我们不能保证搬走它  下面的人不会砸伤
We can't lift it without jeopardizing everyone down here.
所以是时候讨论截肢了
So it's time to discuss amputation.
不
No.
请听我说
Please listen to me.
我们已经在这下面待了近两小时
We've been down here almost two hours.
他们清理乱石的这段时间...
By the time they clear away the rubble--
我们不截她的肢
We are not cutting off her leg.
你不必为了能让他工作轻松些
You don't have to rush through this
而仓促截肢
to make his job easier.
你开玩笑的吧
You kidding me?
腿一直被压着  会有挤压综合症的危险
We leave the leg pinned, we're risking crush syndrome.
那是什么
What's that?
你腿部血液循环不足
Your leg isn't getting enough circulation.
被压时间越长  肌肉坏死越多
The longer it's pinned the more the muscle dies.
那是什么意思  我会瘸吗
So what does that mean, like a limp?
坏死肌肉会释放毒素
Dying muscles release poisons.
我们松开你的腿后
We free your leg,
毒素会随血液回流进入身体系统
the poisons rush back into your system.
会让你心跳停止
It could stop your heart.
芝士汉堡也有这个隐患
So could cheeseburgers.
还是让你的懒弟兄们动手搬碎石吧
Let's get your lazy friends to start moving that pile.
起码两小时后才会出现挤压综合症
She's got two more hours before crush syndrome
她还有时间
could possibly set in.
我们是徒手挖的
We're digging up there by hand.
我不能保证两小时内
I can't guarantee I can get 10 tons of debris
能搬走十吨碎石
pulled off in two hours.
你得试试
Well, you need to try.
那是我的腿
It's my leg.
现在不光要担心挤压综合症
It's not just crush syndrome you gotta worry about, okay?
还有煤气泄漏的危险  会着火的
There's gas leaks. There's fire.
无论我们把这里支撑的多稳固
We can never rule out secondary collapses,
也不能排除二次倒塌的可能性
no matter how much we shore this thing up.
你以为在一大片肮脏的碎石堆里
You think chopping off someone's limb
给人截肢就很安全吗
inside a pile of dirty rocks is safe?
败血症  脂肪栓塞  大出血
Sepsis, fat embolism, a hemorrhage.
这些危险和二次倒塌发生的危险
Those risks are nothing compared to the risk
不可同日而语
of this thing coming down again.
长官  他是个混蛋
Captain, he's a jerk.
但是病人希望这样
But it's what the patient wants.
能请你们再
Can we please just
坚持个把小时吗
give it a couple more hours?
好吧
Yeah.
我去上面给伤员鉴伤分类
I gotta get up to triage.
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, doctor.
豪斯
House.
不用谢我
You don't need to thank me.
我只是讲讲道理罢了
Just makes sense.
请保证你不会让他们给我截肢
Just promise me you won't let them cut off my leg.
我保证
I promise.
这样你感觉好点了吗
Does that make you feel better?
不知怎么的  真的好多了
For some reason, it does.
你的电话能用了
Your phone is working down here.
换了服务商  累积免话费更久
Switched carriers. Better rollover minutes.
说话
Talk.
磁共振成像显示没问题  但是
MRI was clean, but afterwards,
他的眼和鼻开始流血
He started bleeding out of his eyes and nose.
所以确实他在昏倒前就得了病
So there was something wrong before the collapse.
除非只是创伤引起的凝血功能不全
Unless it's just conjunctive coagulopathy from the trauma.
是  是  是  你认为他之前没病
Yeah, yeah, yeah--you don't think he was sick before.
我们懂了  但你错了
We get it! You're wrong.
是大脑感染吗
Brain infection?
对不起  我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
-你去哪了  -做理疗
- Where were you? - Physical therapy.
我电话落在柜子里了
I left my phone in my locker.
感染引起了神经症状
The infection causes neurological symptoms,
遍及全身  弥散性血管内凝血造成出血
goes systemic, and D.I.C. causes the bleed.
不错的理论
Good theory.
可惜他没发烧
Except for the part that there's no fever.
给他做x光静脉造影
Get an x-ray venogram.
看看能不能找出你存在的理由
See if you can find a reason for your existence.
顺便看看有没有静脉窦血栓
Also look for venous sinus thrombosis.
有的话做磁共振时就该看出来
Would have seen it on the mri.
可能是你们忙得没找着吧
Not if you were too busy not looking for it.
我们应该先用x光看看有无脸部骨折
We should x-ray for a facial fracture first.
很可能是简单的外伤造成的
This could all be simple trauma.
照我说的做
Just do what I tell you.
十分钟后回来
Be back in ten minutes.
你要走吗
You're leaving?
这里有很多人都能救你
There's a dozen people here who can save you.
而显然我是唯一能救那家伙的人
I'm apparently the only one who can save this other guy.
等等
W-wait!
别走
Don't go.
汉娜快崩溃了
Hanna's freaking out.
她恐慌症发作
She's having a panic attack.
不能呼吸  要拔掉所有输液管
She can't breathe. She's gonna rip out all her IVs.
那让她安静下来
So calm her down.
她想让你在身边
She wants you.
受宠若惊啊  给她输氧气
I'm flattered. Give her oxygen.
他们不会把氧气送下去的
They won't let O2 down there.
怕爆炸
Fear of explosion.
你得回去
You have to go back.
她需要你  豪斯
She needs you, house.
你回来只是因为我快要崩溃了
You only came back because I freaked out.
对吗
Right?
不是的
Oh, no.
我只是发觉...
I just realized how...
外面的世界是那么混乱而恐怖
big and scary the world is
而这个小地方又是多么的惬意而安全
and how cozy and safe this little place is.
谢谢你
Thank you.
抱歉我真的需要你
I'm sorry I needed you.
给你  打个电话给你老公
Here. Call your husband.
是查理吗
Charlie?
我现在在...
I'm here in...
他们打电话给你了吗
They called you?
他们正在救我
They're helping me.
你要来吗
Are you coming?
我不知道为什么会发生这样的事
I don't know how this could happen.
今天是你的生日  对不起
It's your birthday. I'm so sorry.
看吧  这就是为什么我骗你手机不好用
See? This is why I lied about the phone.
你的血压正在升高
Your bp is spiking,
这会使你腿部的伤口出血速度加快
So you're bleeding faster from your leg wound.
我救治的时间变短
I'm gonna have less time to save it.
挂电话吧
Hang up.
好了  好了  我必须挂掉了
Okay. Okay, they're telling me I have to go.
我太蠢了  不该让你打电话的
That was stupid of me.
你是好人
It was nice.
我可看不出好人是对蠢人的辩驳
I don't see that as a contradiction.
他已经在来的路上了
He was already on his way.
他本来在巴尔的摩
He was in Baltimore,
后来他们都从新闻获知了这里的事故
and they all saw it on the news.
有多少人受伤了
How many people were hurt?
我才说了不能让你的血压上升
What did I tell you about not raising your blood pressure?
我能问问你的腿怎么了吗
Can I ask what's wrong with your leg?
吊车倒在上面了
Crane fell on it.
无巧不成书
Small world.
你可以只说不想回答
You could have just said no.
下一次与人交流时  我会记得的
I'll remember that for my next human contact.
和我一起祈祷好吗
Would you pray with me?
不
No.
我不习惯于鼓励
I'm not in the habit of encouraging
我的病人搞迷信
my patients' superstitions.
这叫什么习惯
How is that a habit?
你还想再被困在倒塌的大楼下吗
You plan on getting trapped under a building again?
我不崇拜上帝
I don't believe in god.
我也不
I don't either.
求你了
Please?
我总觉得...
I always thought...
如果我好好做人
if I did the right thing,
与人为善
if I treated people right,
我就能有好报
then good things would happen to me.
你觉得对吗
You think that's how it works?
我原来不觉得
I didn't use to.
最近我试了试...
Then recently I tried...
现在我不知道这个答案了
Now I don't know.
好消息
Good news.
推进导管进入颈静脉
Advancing catheter through interior jugular vein.
你和豪斯说当时你在做理疗
You told House you were at therapy.
你给整个会议记笔记了
Did you transcribe the entire meeting?
导管插入海绵窦
Entering the cavernous sinus.
你都在周四做理疗的
Your therapy's on thursdays.
改时间了
Got rescheduled.
注射造影剂
Injecting dye.
真的
Really?
我不会乱说的  我们是朋友
I'm not gonna rat you out. We're friends.
我只是想确认你没事
Just wanna make sure you're okay.
没有充盈缺损
No filling defects.
别担心
Don't worry.
我很好
I'm okay.
等我从这里出去了
You think we can be friends
你觉得我们可以做朋友吗
when I get outta here?
当然
Yeah.
我们可以一起去看球赛或者...
We'll catch a ball game or...
群P什么的
Group sex show or something.
把楔子放到那儿去
Put the cribbing in there.
好了  一会横梁抬起来的时候
Okay, now when the beam starts lifting,
你会感觉到疼痛
you're gonna feel pain.
这就像你的脚之前睡着了  现在醒了
It's gonna be like your foot's gone to sleep
比之前疼上成千上万倍
Times a billion.
一会你就知道
You'll notice that
为什么我现在才告诉你了
I'm waiting till now to tell you.
好  我们准备好了
All right. We're ready.
抬横梁
Lifting.
我已经觉得疼了
I'm feeling the pain already.
好事
That's good.
这说明我们的方法用对了
That means the pressure's coming off.
快要让你脱离这里了
Much closer to getting out of here.
来吧
Come on.
把她拉出来
Pull her out.
加把劲
Come on!
那墙在晃动
It's moving!
使劲拽  使劲
Pull hard! Pull!
汉娜
Hanna.
汉娜  该死的  发生什么了
Hanna! What the hell happened?
我想是旁边的梁在我们抬的时候坍塌了
I think the adjacent beam snapped during the lift.
求援  求援  求援
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
我们这里发生了二次坍塌
We had a secondary collapse.
我们没事  你们怎么样
We're all right. How are you guys?
救援队一号  收到求援
Rescue one, copy the mayday.
主通道通畅  救援队正在赶来
Main tunnel is fine. Rescue's on the way.
把这个抬起来
Lift this up.
一  二
One, two--
急救包  给我急救包
Kit. Give me the kit.
好的
All right.
左侧肺没有呼吸音
No breath sounds on the left side.
张力性气胸
Tension pneumothorax.
听着  汉娜  你的一片肺收缩了
Okay, Hanna. One of your lungs is collapsed.
我必须要让它复原  好吗
I'm gonna have to reinflate it, okay?
你最好上去检查一下
You better get back up top
看看有没有割到动脉
and make sure you didn't nick an artery.
我得走了
I'm gonna have to go.
没事的  你很好
That's okay. You're all right.
你真幸运  情况不算太糟
You're lucky this isn't worse.
你知道谁更幸运吗
You know who's even luckier?
你和其他所有
You and just about every other human being
没在下面的人
who wasn't down there.
静脉造影什么结果
What did the venogram say?
正常
Clean.
现在这家伙开始发烧了
Now the guy's starting to spike a fever.
蛛网膜下腔出血
Subarachnoid bleed.
-脑膜炎  -他没说自己的颈部疼痛
- Meningitis? - He didn't say his neck was sore.
因为他哪里都疼
That's 'cause everything's sore.
他刚刚做了一个十五层高的燕式跳水
He just took a 15-story swan dive
一头扎入混凝土  做个腰椎穿刺
into concrete. Do an LP.
我们也得考虑其他感染
We also have to consider other infections.
所以你在建议我们做个腰椎穿刺
So you're suggesting we do an LP?
我想是的
I guess I am.
你真有才
Genius.
坏消息
Hey, bad news.
坍塌的缘故
Because of the collapse,
让我们不能再试用气袋抬横梁的办法了
we can't try the airbag again
除非把上面的所有东西清除干净
until we get everything off the top.
那至少要五六个小时
Be five, six hours at least.
那必须截肢了
Then we have to amputate.
不行
No.
已经四个小时了
It's been four hours already.
本来就希望渺小  现在  更加是妄想
It used to be a long shot. Now it's...crazy.
挤压综合症基本上就是钾元素堆积
Crush syndrome is basically a buildup of potassium.
若我们把钾去除
If we remove potassium--
不是已经给她输过碳酸氢钠了吗
We're already treating with sodium bicarbonate.
但没加注葡萄糖和胰岛素
But not with glucose and insulin.
急救包里有葡萄糖
We have glucose in the kit.
这里肯定有糖尿病患者
There's gotta be a diabetic here somewhere.
你想在这种非医疗环境下
You wanna dose the insulin
给她用胰岛素
here in a non-hospital setting?
简直是疯了  不值得
That is insane! It's not worth it.
是吗  我发现这里
Really? 'cause I think
只有我才知道一条腿是多么重要
I'm the only one here who knows what a leg is worth.
幸好  你不是负责人  他才是
And fortunately, you're not the one in charge--he is.
他清楚  若汉娜到时候告他没有
And he knows that I'd testify against him
尝试所有办法就截掉了她的腿
if Hanna sues for cutting off a leg
我会做出对他不利的证明
without exhausting every option.
让我们单独谈一下
Give us a minute?
我知道你在生气
I know you're angry,
但请你不要为了报复我
But please don't put her life at risk
而拿她的生命开玩笑
just to get back at me.
是吗
Really?
原来一切都围绕着你
So this is all about you now.
一听说我订婚的事后
You took her side against me
你就和她站一边  跟我作对
right after you heard about my engagement.
是啊  肯定是这个原因了
Yeah. That must be it.
你又不是个可怜的自恋狂
It's not that you're a pathetic narcissist.
我不爱你
I don't love you.
请你  接受现实
So just...accept it
继续自己的生活
and move on with your life
别再让其他人痛苦了
instead of making everyone miserable.
太精彩了
That's great.
一个和幼稚男恋爱的中年单身母亲
A life lesson from a middle-aged single mom
给我讲人生哲学
who's dating a man-child.
去你的
Screw you.
我厌倦了替你找借口
I'm sick of making excuses for you.
厌倦了别人得捧着你  顺着你
I'm sick of other people having to tiptoe around you
为了让你好好活着
and make their own lives worse
而把自己的生活搞得一团糟
while they try to keep you from collapsing.
我说完了
I'm done.
精彩极了
Fantastic.
离我的病人远点
Just stay away from my patient.
你到底想怎么样  豪斯
What are you clinging to, House?
为了保全腿而不顾她的生命安危吗
You're gonna risk her life just to save her leg?
就像你当年的选择很明智  是不是
Really worked out well for you, didn't it?
说真的  你的人生都得到了些什么
What do you have in your life, honestly?
跟我说说
Tell me.
我在向前进
I'm moving on.
威尔森也在向前进
Wilson is moving on.
而你  你一无所有  豪斯
And you...you've got nothing, House.
一无所有
Nothing.
我现在要下去
I'm going down there,
劝服她截掉腿
and I'm gonna convince her to let me cut her leg off.
若你还有点良知的话  就别再插手
If you have any decency left, you'll just stay out of it.
不
No.
豪斯医生允诺过的
Dr. House promised.
若有其它办法的话
If there was any other way...
现在不疼了  我能等
It doesn't hurt right now. I can wait.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
你告诉她
Tell her.
汉娜
Hanna...
我们不得不截掉你的腿
We have to amputate your leg.
不
No.
你说了  还有时间的
You said... that there was time.
之前是有  但现在已经到时候了
There was. And it's run out.
不
No.
你问我是怎么伤了腿的
You asked me how I'd hurt my leg.
那里面有个血块  肌肉在坏死
I had a blood clot, and the muscle was dying.
所有的医生都劝我截肢
And I had all these doctors telling me I should amputate,
我拒绝了  他们就做了个
and I said no, and they did this...
风险很大的手术
very risky operation.
我差点死了
I almost died.
但你保住了腿
But you saved your leg.
我希望当初没有
I wish I hadn't.
他们切除了拳头大的一块肌肉
They cut out a chunk of muscle about the size of my fist,
留给我这么个残缺
and they left me with this mutilated,
没用的东西
useless thing.
我要忍受疼痛  每天都是
I'm in pain...every day.
这改变了我
It changed me.
让我成为了一个更无情的人
Made me a harder person,
一个更糟糕的人
a worse person.
结果现在
And now...
我孤身一人
now I'm alone.
你不会想要像我一样的
You don't want to be like me.
你有个爱你的丈夫
You got a husband who loves you.
你有朋友  还可以生儿育女
You have friends. You can start a family.
你有自己的生活
You have a life.
而这个  只是条腿而已
And this... this is just a leg.
好吧
Okay.
我来吧
I got it.
我不能用麻药让你昏迷
I can't put you out.
那会严重抑制你的呼吸
It could depress your respiration too much.
这个能稍微减轻疼痛
This should take away some of the pain.
会很快吗
Will it be quick?
我要用手术刀切开表皮
I'll use a scalpel to slice through the skin,
肌肉  还有脂肪
muscle, and fat.
这一步应该很快
That should go pretty fast.
到达骨头的时候
Then I'll switch over to the electric saw
再用电锯
when I get to the bone.
有两根骨头  大概有扫帚把那么粗
It's two bones... about as thick as a broomstick.
锯断才能停下
Takes about as long to get through.
我会尽量贴紧水泥块切
I'm gonna cut as close to the concrete as I can,
尽可能多的保住腿
save as much of your limb as possible.
回到医院再做整形手术
Then the orthopedic surgeons back at the hospital
进行清理  给你装个假肢
will clean you up, have you fitted for a prosthetic.
你马上就能围着我转圈圈了
You'll be running circles around me in no time.
会有多疼
How bad will it hurt?
是你从未经历过的剧痛
Like nothing you've ever felt before.
汉娜
Hanna.
哦  宝贝
Oh...baby.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
-别再说了  -你那么爱我的腿
- Shut up.  - You always loved my legs.
我不在乎你的腿
I don't care about your legs.
宝贝  我爱你
Baby, I love you.
我爱的是你
I love you.
我爱你
怎么了
What?
他昏迷了
He's fallen into a coma.
脊髓液正常  但是
LP was clean, but...
各项生命体征多少
What are his vitals?
让一下警官
Excuse me, officer.
什么警官
What do you mean, officer?
条子什么时候去的
How long has there been a cop there?
记不清了  大约十分钟前吧
I don't know. Ten minutes.
他再接受询问的时候昏迷的
He was being questioned when he fell into the coma.
在他出现其他症状前
Was anything else making him nervous
还有别的事情让他紧张焦虑吗
or worried before his other symptoms?
内出血和发烧之前
He was claustrophobic right
他出现幽闭恐怖症症状
before the bleed and before the fever.
我们告诉他他可能是睡着了
We told him that he probably did fall asleep.
血压升高了吗
Was his BP spiking?
是  但不是他第一个症状出现的原因
But that didn't cause his first symptom.
就是  都是咖啡因惹的祸
Yeah, it did. All the caffeine.
我们原以为他的问题在他的厕所那
We thought the problem was in his toilet--
当然  我的意思是  他的头
By that, of course, I mean his head.
这让我们关注错了焦点
Which distracted us from the fact
其实就是他的下水道堵住了
that it could have been just a clog in his sewer pipe,
下水道就是指他的脊髓
and by that, of course, I mean his spinal cord.
还有一堆理所当然的事情  你们懂的
And blah, blah, blah, blah. You get the idea.
一个蛛网状囊肿长在他的下部脊椎上
An arachnoid cyst on his lower spine.
所以我们没发现
That's why we missed it.
他足足坐了十个小时
He's been sitting ten hours a day.
使得他的脊髓液压飙升
Spiked his spinal fluid pressure.
给他做个CT
Run a CT--
高压72  低压42  汉娜
BP's 72 over 42. Hanna?
-汉娜  -我喘不上气来
- Hanna?  - I can't breathe.
我喘不上气来
I can't breathe.
双肺呼吸顺畅  不是气胸
Breath sounds bilaterally. It's not another pneumothorax.
颈静脉没有突起  没有填塞
Neck veins flat. There's no tamponade.
该死的  我等的太久了
Damn it. I waited too long.
汉娜  你的肺部有血块
Hanna, you've got a clot in your lung.
我来处理好
I'm gonna fix this.
注射溶栓剂
IV streptokinase.
发生了什么  这是怎么一回事
What's happening. What's going on?
除非我们打碎血块  负责她没法呼入氧气
Her body won't get any oxygen unless we can bust the clot.
这是血液稀释剂
This is a blood thinner.
她不会有事吧
Is she gonna be all right?
这会让她出血量增加
It's gonna make her bleed more.
那个我们再处理
We'll take care of that next.
不管用
It's not busting the clot.
可能在她的心脏里
Maybe it's her heart.
怎么了
What?
不是血块
It's not a clot.
是脂肪栓
It's a fat embolism.
截肢导致的
From the amputation.
那我们该怎么办
Okay. So--so what can we do?
想想办法
Come on.
做点什么  求你了  做点什么
Do something. Please, please, do something.
想想办法啊  伙计们 求你们了
Come on, guys, do something. Come on.
求你们了  做点什么
Come on. Please, come on, do something!
想想办法救救她啊
Come on, do something! Do something!
没什么办法能预防脂肪栓形成
There's no way to prevent a fat embolism.
就算截肢是在手术室里做的
Even if you'd done this in an O.R.,
也救不了她
Couldn't have saved her.
别太自责
You can't blame yourself for her death.
这不是你的错
This wasn't your fault.
这才是问题的关键
That's the point!
我能做的都做对了  但她还是死了
I did everything right. She died anyway.
你怎么会认为
Why the hell do you think
这能让我好受点
that would make me feel any better?
你不能单独留在这
You shouldn't be alone right now.
你在流血
You're bleeding.
作为我的手下  我命令你
I'm gonna give you a task as an employee.
闪 开
Get out of my way.
那是什么
What's that?
我准备请假
I'm asking for some time off.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
显然不好
Obviously not.
你打算三步并作两步冲上来
You going to leap across the room
夺走我的药
and grab them out of my hand?
不
No.
你想回到过去嗑药的日子这是你的选择
It's your choice if you want to go back on drugs.
好吧
Okay.
想让你知道
Just so you know,
我正努力与堕落作斗争
I'm finding it hard to see the downside.
你的肩膀需要重新包扎一下
You need to re-bandage your shoulder.
这就是你来的原因  福曼让你来的
Is that why you're here? Foreman sent you?
不是
No.
你是来冲我大喊大叫的
You here to yell at me again?
不是
No.
那我就不知道原因了
Well, I'm running out of ideas.
卢卡斯
Lucas...
又是他
Oh, great.
你又觉得不自在了
You're feeling uncomfortable again?
难道是刚从
Probably means you just got back
拉斯维加斯闪婚回来
from some quickie wedding in Vegas
还是你已经怀孕了
or you're already pregnant.
我俩分手了
I ended it.
什么
What?
我很迷茫  豪斯
I'm stuck, House.
我总是想抬头向前看
I keep wanting to move forward.
想抛掉过去  但是我做不到
I keep wanting to move on, and I can't.
我的新房  未婚夫
I mean, my new house, with my new fiance,
我想到这一切的时候脑中只有你
and all I can think about is you.
我只是想知道
I just need to know
你我到底有没有可能
If you and I can work.
你认为我自救有望
You think I can fix myself?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是这个世界上最失败的人
'cause I'm the most screwed-up person in the world.
我知道
I know.
但是我爱你
I love you.
我多希望我不爱你
I wish I didn't.
但我却情不自已
But I can't help it.
这不是幻觉吧
How do I know I'm not hallucinating?
你吃药了吗
Did you take the vicodin?
没有
No.
那就是真的
Then I think we're okay.